<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><MD_Metadata xmlns:gts="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/gts" xmlns:gco="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/gco" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:srv="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/srv" xmlns:gmx="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/gmx" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml" xmlns="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/gmd">
    <fileIdentifier>
        <gco:CharacterString>d1c32af3212341869b3c810f1a215824</gco:CharacterString>
    </fileIdentifier>
    <characterSet>
        <MD_CharacterSetCode codeList="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#MD_CharacterSetCode" codeListValue="utf8" codeSpace="ISOTC211/19115">utf8</MD_CharacterSetCode>
    </characterSet>
    <hierarchyLevel>
        <MD_ScopeCode codeList="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#MD_ScopeCode" codeListValue="dataset" codeSpace="ISOTC211/19115">dataset</MD_ScopeCode>
    </hierarchyLevel>
    <hierarchyLevelName>
        <gco:CharacterString>dataset</gco:CharacterString>
    </hierarchyLevelName>
    <contact>
        <CI_ResponsibleParty>
            <contactInfo>
                <CI_Contact>
                    <address>
                        <CI_Address>
                            <electronicMailAddress>
                                <gco:CharacterString>nifc_public_data@firenet.gov</gco:CharacterString>
                            </electronicMailAddress>
                        </CI_Address>
                    </address>
                </CI_Contact>
            </contactInfo>
            <role>
                <CI_RoleCode codeList="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#CI_RoleCode" codeListValue="pointOfContact" codeSpace="ISOTC211/19115">pointOfContact</CI_RoleCode>
            </role>
        </CI_ResponsibleParty>
    </contact>
    <dateStamp>
        <gco:Date>2023-03-14</gco:Date>
    </dateStamp>
    <metadataStandardName>
        <gco:CharacterString>ISO 19139 Geographic Information - Metadata - Implementation Specification</gco:CharacterString>
    </metadataStandardName>
    <metadataStandardVersion>
        <gco:CharacterString>2007</gco:CharacterString>
    </metadataStandardVersion>
    <identificationInfo>
        <MD_DataIdentification>
            <citation>
                <CI_Citation>
                    <title>
                        <gco:CharacterString>WFIGS Current Interagency Fire Perimeters</gco:CharacterString>
                    </title>
                    <date gco:nilReason="missing"/>
                </CI_Citation>
            </citation>
            <abstract>
                <gco:CharacterString>The Wildland Fire Interagency Geospatial Services (WFIGS) Group provides authoritative geospatial data products under the interagency Wildland Fire Data Program. Hosted in the National Interagency Fire Center ArcGIS Online Organization (The NIFC Org), WFIGS provides both internal and public facing data, accessible in a variety of formats.This service includes perimeters for wildland fire incidents that meet the following criteria:Categorized in the IRWIN (Integrated Reporting of Wildland Fire Information) integration service as a Wildfire (WF) or Prescribed Fire (RX)Has not been declared contained, controlled, nor outHas not had fire report records completed (certified)Is Valid and not &amp;quot;quarantined&amp;quot; in IRWIN due to potential conflicts with other recordsAttribution of the source polygon is set to a Feature Access of Public, a Feature Status of Approved, and an Is Visible setting of YesPerimeters are not available for every incident. For a complete set of features that meet the same IRWIN criteria, see the Current Wildland Fire Locations service.&amp;quot;Fall-off&amp;quot; rules are used to ensure that stale records are not retained. Records are removed from this service under the following conditions:If the fire size is less than 10 acres (Size Class A or B) and fire information has not been updated in more than 3 daysFire size is between 10 and 100 acres (Size Class C) and fire information hasn't been updated in more than 8 daysFire size is larger than 100 acres (Size Class D-L) but fire information hasn't been updated in more than 14 days.Fires from previous calendar years are excluded.Fire size used in the fall off rules is from the IRWIN IncidentSize field.Fires that are no longer in the Current Wildland Fire Perimeter service will be displayed in the Wildland Fire Perimeters Year to Date and/or the 'Full History' service. Criteria were determined by an NWCG Geospatial Subcommittee task group. Data are refreshed every 5 minutes. Changes in the perimeter source may take up to 15 minutes to display.Perimeters are pulled from multiple sources with rules in place to ensure the most current or most authoritative shape is used.Fall-off rules are enforced hourly.Attributes and their definitions can be found below. More detail about the NWCG Wildland Fire Event Polygon standard can be found here.Attributes:poly_SourceOIDThe OBJECTID value of the source record in the source dataset providing the polygon.poly_IncidentNameThe incident name as stored in the polygon source record.poly_MapMethodThe mapping method with which the polygon was derived.poly_GISAcresThe acreage of the polygon as stored in the polygon source record.poly_CreateDateSystem generated date for the date time the source polygon record was created (stored in UTC).poly_DateCurrentSystem generated date for the date time the source polygon record was last edited (stored in UTC).poly_PolygonDateTimeRepresents the date time that the polygon data was captured.poly_IRWINIDIRWIN ID stored in the polygon record.poly_FORIDFORID stored in the polygon record.poly_Acres_AutoCalcSystem calculated acreage of the polygon (geodesic WGS84 acres).poly_SourceGlobalIDThe GlobalID value of the source record in the source dataset providing the polygon.poly_SourceThe source dataset providing the polygon.attr_SourceOIDThe OBJECTID value of the source record in the source dataset providing the attribution.attr_ABCDMiscA FireCode used by USDA FS to track and compile cost information for emergency initial attack fire suppression expenditures. for A, B, C &amp;amp; D size class fires on FS lands.attr_ADSPermissionStateIndicates the permission hierarchy that is currently being applied when a system utilizes the UpdateIncident operation.attr_ContainmentDateTimeThe date and time a wildfire was declared contained. attr_ControlDateTimeThe date and time a wildfire was declared under control.attr_CreatedBySystemArcGIS Server Username of system that created the IRWIN Incident record.attr_IncidentSizeReported for a fire. The minimum size is 0.1.attr_DiscoveryAcresAn estimate of acres burning upon the discovery of the fire. More specifically when the fire is first reported by the first person that calls in the fire.  The estimate should include number of acres within the current perimeter of a specific, individual incident, including unburned and unburnable islands.attr_DispatchCenterIDA unique identifier for a dispatch center responsible for supporting the incident.attr_EstimatedCostToDateThe total estimated cost of the incident to date.attr_FinalAcresReported final acreage of incident.attr_FFReportApprovedByTitleThe title of the person that approved the final fire report for the incident.attr_FFReportApprovedByUnitNWCG Unit ID associated with the individual who approved the final report for the incident.attr_FFReportApprovedDateThe date that the final fire report was approved for the incident.attr_FireBehaviorGeneralA general category describing the manner in which the fire is currently reacting to the influences of fuel, weather, and topography. attr_FireBehaviorGeneral1A more specific category further describing the general fire behavior (manner in which the fire is currently reacting to the influences of fuel, weather, and topography). attr_FireBehaviorGeneral2A more specific category further describing the general fire behavior (manner in which the fire is currently reacting to the influences of fuel, weather, and topography). attr_FireBehaviorGeneral3A more specific category further describing the general fire behavior (manner in which the fire is currently reacting to the influences of fuel, weather, and topography). attr_FireCauseBroad classification of the reason the fire occurred identified as human, natural or unknown. attr_FireCauseGeneralAgency or circumstance which started a fire or set the stage for its occurrence; source of a fire's ignition. For statistical purposes, fire causes are further broken into specific causes. attr_FireCauseSpecificA further categorization of each General Fire Cause to indicate more specifically the agency or circumstance which started a fire or set the stage for its occurrence; source of a fire's ignition. attr_FireCodeA code used within the interagency wildland fire community to track and compile cost information for emergency fire suppression expenditures for the incident. attr_FireDepartmentIDThe U.S. Fire Administration (USFA) has created a national database of Fire Departments.  Most Fire Departments do not have an NWCG Unit ID and so it is the intent of the IRWIN team to create a new field that includes this data element to assist the National Association of State Foresters (NASF) with data collection.attr_FireDiscoveryDateTimeThe date and time a fire was reported as discovered or confirmed to exist.  May also be the start date for reporting purposes.attr_FireMgmtComplexityThe highest management level utilized to manage a wildland fire event. attr_FireOutDateTimeThe date and time when a fire is declared out. attr_FireStrategyConfinePercentIndicates the percentage of the incident area where the fire suppression strategy of &amp;quot;Confine&amp;quot; is being implemented.attr_FireStrategyFullSuppPrcntIndicates the percentage of the incident area where the fire suppression strategy of &amp;quot;Full Suppression&amp;quot; is being implemented.attr_FireStrategyMonitorPercentIndicates the percentage of the incident area where the fire suppression strategy of &amp;quot;Monitor&amp;quot; is being implemented.attr_FireStrategyPointZonePrcntIndicates the percentage of the incident area where the fire suppression strategy of &amp;quot;Point Zone Protection&amp;quot; is being implemented.attr_FSJobCodeA code use to indicate the Forest Service job accounting code for the incident.  This is specific to the Forest Service.  Usually displayed as 2 char prefix on FireCode.attr_FSOverrideCodeA code used to indicate the Forest Service override code for the incident.  This is specific to the Forest Service.  Usually displayed as a 4 char suffix on FireCode.  For example, if the FS is assisting DOI, an override of 1502 will be used.attr_GACCA code that identifies one of the wildland fire geographic area coordination center at the point of origin for the incident.A geographic area coordination center is a facility that is used for the coordination of agency or jurisdictional resources in support of one or more incidents within a geographic coordination area.attr_ICS209ReportDateTimeThe date and time of the latest approved ICS-209 report.attr_ICS209RptForTimePeriodFromThe date and time of the beginning of the time period for the current ICS-209 submission.attr_ICS209RptForTimePeriodToThe date and time of the end of the time period for the current ICS-209 submission.  attr_ICS209ReportStatusThe version of the ICS-209 report (initial, update, or final). There should never be more than one initial report, but there can be numerous updates, and even multiple finals (as determined by business rules).attr_IncidentManagementOrgThe incident management organization for the incident, which may be a Type 1, 2, or 3 Incident Management Team (IMT), a Unified Command, a Unified Command with an IMT, National Incident Management Organization (NIMO), etc.  This field is null if no team is assigned.attr_IncidentNameThe name assigned to an incident.attr_IncidentShortDescriptionGeneral descriptive location of the incident such as the number of miles from an identifiable town. attr_IncidentTypeCategoryThe Event Category is a sub-group of the Event Kind code and description. The Event Category further breaks down the Event Kind into more specific event categories.attr_IncidentTypeKindA general, high-level code and description of the types of incidents and planned events to which the interagency wildland fire community responds.attr_InitialLatitudeThe latitude location of the initial reported point of origin specified in decimal degrees.attr_InitialLongitudeThe longitude location of the initial reported point of origin specified in decimal degrees.attr_InitialResponseAcresAn estimate of acres burning at the time of initial response. More specifically when the IC arrives and performs initial size up.  The minimum size must be 0.1.  The estimate should include number of acres within the current perimeter of a specific, individual incident, including unburned and unburnable islands.attr_InitialResponseDateTimeThe date/time of the initial response to the incident. More specifically when the IC arrives and performs initial size up.  attr_IrwinIDUnique identifier assigned to each incident record in IRWIN.attr_IsFireCauseInvestigatedIndicates if an investigation is underway or was completed to determine the cause of a fire.attr_IsFSAssistedIndicates if the Forest Service provided assistance on an incident outside their jurisdiction.attr_IsMultiJurisdictionalIndicates if the incident covers multiple jurisdictions.attr_IsReimbursableIndicates the cost of an incident may be another agency’s responsibility.attr_IsTrespassIndicates if the incident is a trespass claim or if a bill will be pursued.attr_IsUnifiedCommandIndicates whether the incident is being managed under Unified Command.  Unified Command is an application of the Incident Command System used when there is more than one agency with incident jurisdiction or when incidents cross political jurisdictions. Under Unified Command, agencies work together through their designated Incident Commanders at a single incident command post to establish common objectives and issue a single Incident Action Plan.attr_LocalIncidentIdentifierA number or code that uniquely identifies an incident for a particular local fire management organization within a particular calendar year.attr_ModifiedBySystemArcGIS Server username of system that last modified the IRWIN Incident record.attr_PercentContainedIndicates the percent of incident area that is no longer active.  Reference definition in fire line handbook when developing standard.attr_PercentPerimToBeContainedIndicates the percent of perimeter left to be completed. This entry is appropriate for full suppression, point/zone protection, and confine fires, or any combination of these strategies. This entry is not used for wildfires managed entirely under a monitor strategy.  (Note: Value is not currently being passed by ICS-209)attr_POOCityThe closest city to the incident point of origin.attr_POOCountyThe County Name identifying the county or equivalent entity at point of origin designated at the time of collection.attr_POODispatchCenterIDA unique identifier for the dispatch center that intersects with the incident point of origin. attr_POOFipsThe code which uniquely identifies counties and county equivalents.  The first two digits are the FIPS State code and the last three are the county code within the state.attr_POOJurisdictionalAgencyThe agency having land and resource management responsibility for a incident as provided by federal, state or local law. attr_POOJurisdictionalUnitNWCG Unit Identifier to identify the unit with jurisdiction for the land where the point of origin of a fire falls.                                                                                 attr_POOJurisdictUnitParentUnitThe unit ID for the parent entity, such as a BLM State Office or USFS Regional Office, that resides over the Jurisdictional Unit.attr_POOLandownerCategoryMore specific classification of land ownership within land owner kinds identifying the deeded owner at the point of origin at the time of the incident.attr_POOLandownerKindBroad classification of land ownership identifying the deeded owner at the point of origin at the time of the incident.attr_POOLegalDescPrincipalMeridThe principal meridian of the legal description (section, township, range) of the incident at point of origin.attr_POOLegalDescQtrThe quarter section of the legal description (section, township, range) of the incident at point of origin.attr_POOLegalDescQtrQtrThe quarter/quarter section of the legal description (section, township, range) of the incident at point of origin.attr_POOLegalDescRangeThe range of the legal description (section, township, range) of the incident at point of origin.attr_POOLegalDescSectionThe section of the legal description (section, township, range) of the incident at point of origin.attr_POOLegalDescTownshipThe township of the legal description (section, township, range) of the incident at point of origin.attr_POOPredictiveServiceAreaIDThe predictive service area ID where the incidents point of origin is location.  Predictive Service Areas (PSAs) are geographic areas of similar climate based on statistical correlation of Remote Automated Weather Stations (RAWS) data.attr_POOProtectingAgencyIndicates the agency that has protection responsibility at the point of origin.attr_POOProtectingUnitNWCG Unit responsible for providing direct incident management and services to a an incident pursuant to its jurisdictional responsibility or as specified by law, contract or agreement.                                                                                                               Definition Extension: - Protection can be re-assigned by agreement. - The nature and extent of the incident determines protection (for example Wildfire vs. All Hazard.)attr_POOStateThe State alpha code identifying the state or equivalent entity at point of origin.attr_PredominantFuelGroupThe fuel majority fuel model type that best represents fire behavior in the incident area, grouped into one of seven categories.attr_PredominantFuelModelDescribes the type of fuels found within the  majority of the incident area.  attr_PrimaryFuelModelThe fuel model which best represents the primary carrier of the fire for the reporting period.attr_SecondaryFuelModelThe fuel model which best represents the secondary carrier of the fire for the reporting period.attr_TotalIncidentPersonnelThe total number of personnel assigned. Includes overhead, crewmembers, helicopter crewmember, engine crewmembers, camp crew people, etc.attr_UniqueFireIdentifierUnique identifier assigned to each wildland fire.  yyyy = calendar year, SSUUUU = POO protecting unit identifier (5 or 6 characters), xxxxxx = local incident identifier (6 to 10 characters) attr_FORIDUnique identifier assigned to each incident record in the FODR database.attr_WFDSSDecisionStatusIndicates the state of the WFDSS decision and/or if a WFDSS decision has been approved for the incident.  This information is helpful in resolving conflicts between incident records.attr_OrganizationalAssessmentThe Organizational Assessment is part of the Wildland Fire Risk and Complexity Assessment (RCA) that was implemented by NWCG in January 2014, which guides Agency Administrators in their management organization selection, both in escalating and moderating situations.  The Organizational Assessment can be compared with the current Incident Management Organization and many other incident level data elements over the life of the fire. It may not always match the current Incident Management Organization value. The authority for producing the Organizational Assessment lies with the incident commander (NWCG PMS-210), thus, the Organizational Assessment can change independent of the published decision. attr_StratDecisionPublishDateThe Decision Publish Date represents the date Agency Administrators published (approved) the Strategic Decision document. New decisions can be created and published at any time until the incident has been called out.attr_CreatedOnDateTime_dtDate/time that the IRWIN Incident record was created.attr_ModifiedOnDateTime_dtDate/time that the IRWIN Incident record was last modified.attr_SourceThe source dataset from which the attribution for the record is derived.attr_IsCpxChildIndicates whether the incident is part of a Complex or not. &amp;quot;0&amp;quot; for no, &amp;quot;1&amp;quot; for yes.attr_CpxNameThe Incident Name of the Complex that is the parent of the incident.attr_CpxIDThe IRWIN ID for the Complex record that is the parent of the incident.attr_SourceGlobalIDThe GlobalID value of the source record in the source dataset</gco:CharacterString>
            </abstract>
            <purpose>
                <gco:CharacterString>Best available perimeters for recent and ongoing wildland fires in the United States</gco:CharacterString>
            </purpose>
            <credit>
                <gco:CharacterString>US Department of Interior Office of Wildland Fire: IRWIN,
USDA Forest Service,
National Park Service, Fish and Wildlife Service, Bureau of Indian Affairs, and Bureau of Land Management,
National Association of State Foresters,
US Fire Administration,
National Wildfire Coordinating Group</gco:CharacterString>
            </credit>
            <descriptiveKeywords>
                <MD_Keywords>
                    <keyword>
                        <gco:CharacterString>WFIGS</gco:CharacterString>
                    </keyword>
                    <keyword>
                        <gco:CharacterString>Perimeters</gco:CharacterString>
                    </keyword>
                    <keyword>
                        <gco:CharacterString>CY_wildlandfire_opendata</gco:CharacterString>
                    </keyword>
                </MD_Keywords>
            </descriptiveKeywords>
            <resourceConstraints>
                <MD_Constraints>
                    <useLimitation>
                        <gco:CharacterString>The National Interagency Fire Center shall not be held liable for improper or incorrect use of the data described and/or contained herein. These data and related graphics (i.e. GIF or JPG format files) are not legal documents and are not intended to be used as such. The information contained in these data is dynamic and may change over time. The data are not better than the original sources from which they were derived. It is the responsibility of the data user to use the data appropriately and consistent within the limitations of geospatial data in general and these data in particular. The National Fire Center gives no warranty, expressed or implied, as to the accuracy, reliability, or completeness of these data. No warranty expressed or implied is made regarding the utility of the data on other systems for general or scientific purposes, nor shall the act of distribution constitute any such warranty. This disclaimer applies both to individual use of the data and aggregate use with other data. </gco:CharacterString>
                    </useLimitation>
                </MD_Constraints>
            </resourceConstraints>
            <resourceConstraints>
                <MD_LegalConstraints>
                    <accessConstraints>
                        <MD_RestrictionCode codeList="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#MD_RestrictionCode" codeListValue="otherRestrictions" codeSpace="ISOTC211/19115">otherRestrictions</MD_RestrictionCode>
                    </accessConstraints>
                    <otherConstraints>
                        <gco:CharacterString>Other Constraints</gco:CharacterString>
                    </otherConstraints>
                </MD_LegalConstraints>
            </resourceConstraints>
            <resourceConstraints>
                <MD_LegalConstraints>
                    <useConstraints>
                        <MD_RestrictionCode codeList="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#MD_RestrictionCode" codeListValue="otherRestrictions" codeSpace="ISOTC211/19115">otherRestrictions</MD_RestrictionCode>
                    </useConstraints>
                    <otherConstraints>
                        <gco:CharacterString>Other Constraints</gco:CharacterString>
                    </otherConstraints>
                </MD_LegalConstraints>
            </resourceConstraints>
            <language gco:nilReason="missing"/>
            <characterSet>
                <MD_CharacterSetCode codeList="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#MD_CharacterSetCode" codeListValue="utf8" codeSpace="ISOTC211/19115">utf8</MD_CharacterSetCode>
            </characterSet>
        </MD_DataIdentification>
    </identificationInfo>
    <distributionInfo>
        <MD_Distribution>
            <transferOptions>
                <MD_DigitalTransferOptions>
                    <onLine>
                        <CI_OnlineResource>
                            <linkage>
                                <URL>https://services3.arcgis.com/T4QMspbfLg3qTGWY/arcgis/rest/services/WFIGS_Interagency_Perimeters_Current/FeatureServer</URL>
                            </linkage>
                        </CI_OnlineResource>
                    </onLine>
                </MD_DigitalTransferOptions>
            </transferOptions>
        </MD_Distribution>
    </distributionInfo>
</MD_Metadata>
